{
    "Food and Drink": {
        "q1": {
            "question": "Which traditional Indian dish is made with basmati rice, spices, and meat or vegetables, often served with raita and naan bread?",
            "answer": "Biryani"
        },
        "q2": {
            "question": "Name the fermented tea beverage that originated in China and is now popular in many countries around the world",
            "answer": "Kombucha"
        },
        "q3": {
            "question": "Which traditional Japanese soup is made with tofu, seaweed and a paste of the same name?",
            "answer": "Miso"
        },
        "q4": {
            "question": "What is the name of the traditional Mexican dish made with a corn or flour tortilla, filled with various ingredients, and then folded or rolled up?",
            "answer": "Taco"
        },
        "q5": {
            "question": "What is the name of the Italian dish made with Arborio rice, broth, and various ingredients, such as mushrooms, seafood, or vegetables?",
            "answer": "Risotto"
        },
        "q6": {
            "question": "Name the fermented milk drink that originated in the Caucasus region and is now popular in many countries around the world?",
            "answer": "Kefir"
        },
        "q7": {
            "question": "What is the name of the Middle Eastern dip made with chickpeas, tahini, lemon juice, and garlic?",
            "answer": "Houmus"
        },
        "q8": {
            "question": "What is the name of the Chinese dish made with stir-fried noodles, vegetables, and meat or seafood, often served in a savory sauce?",
            "answer": "Chow Mein"
        },
        "q9": {
            "question": "What is the national dish of Spain, made with rice, saffron, and various meats, seafood, and vegetables?",
            "answer": "Paella"
        },
        "q10": {
            "question": "What is the national dish of Thailand?",
            "answer": "Pad Thai"
        },
        "q11": {
            "question": "What is the name of the traditional French stew made with beef, vegetables, and red wine?",
            "answer": "Beef Bourguignon"
        },
        "q12": {
            "question": "Name the traditional Korean dish that is made with spicy fermented vegetables, usually cabbage",
            "answer": "Kimchi"
        },
        "q13": {
            "question": "What is the name of the traditional Greek dip made with yogurt, cucumber, garlic, and dill?",
            "answer": "Tzatziki"
        },
        "q14": {
            "question": "Which traditional Scottish dish is made with sheep organs, oats, and spices, cooked in a sheep's stomach?",
            "answer": "Haggis"
        },
        "q15": {
            "question": "What 'C' is a South American dish of marinated raw fish?",
            "answer": "Ceviche"
        },
        "q16": {
            "question": "If you were in Italy eating Cassata, what type of foodstuff would it be?",
            "answer": "Ice Cream"
        },
        "q17": {
            "question": "In the Uk it is known as Bubble and Squeak, but what is the equivalent known as in Ireland?",
            "answer": "Colcannon"
        },
        "q18": {
            "question": "What is the main ingredient for the German Blutwurst?",
            "answer": "Blood"
        },
        "q19": {
            "question": "Lincolnshire sausage is flavoured with which herb?",
            "answer": "Sage"
        },
        "q20": {
            "question": "What are 'Angels on horseback'?",
            "answer": "Oysters wrapped in bacon"
        }
    },
    "General Knowledge": {
        "q1": {
            "question": "What notable feat did Portuguese explorer Ferdinand Magellan complete in 1522?",
            "answer": "First person to circumnavigate the globe"
        },
        "q2": {
            "question": "Lake Victoria is the largest lake on which continent?",
            "answer": "Africa"
        },
        "q3": {
            "question": "Who wrote the novel 'Pride and Prejudice'?",
            "answer": "Jane Austen"
        },
        "q4": {
            "question": "Known for his contribution to physics and mathematics, who was the first person to discover the law of gravity?",
            "answer": "Sir Isaac Newton"
        },
        "q5": {
            "question": "Located in western Pacific Ocean and reaching a depth of 11km, what is the name of the deepest point in the ocean?",
            "answer": "The Mariana Trench"
        },
        "q6": {
            "question": "Who directed the 1975 film 'Jaws'?",
            "answer": "Steven Spielberg"
        },
        "q7": {
            "question": "Alexander Graham Bell is best known for patenting which invention that revolutionised communication in 1876?",
            "answer": "Telephone"
        },
        "q8": {
            "question": "Who painted the famous artwork 'The Last Supper'?",
            "answer": "Leonardo da Vinci"
        },
        "q9": {
            "question": "Who wrote the novel 'The Catcher in the Rye'?",
            "answer": "J.D. Salinger"
        },
        "q10": {
            "question": "What is the name of the largest active volcano in Europe?",
            "answer": "Mount Etna"
        },
        "q11": {
            "question": "What is the name of the world's largest coral reef system, located off the coast of Australia?",
            "answer": "The Great Barrier Reef"
        },
        "q12": {
            "question": "Who wrote the Harry Potter book series?",
            "answer": "JK Rowling"
        },
        "q13": {
            "question": "What is the name of the river that flows through Paris?",
            "answer": "The Seine"
        },
        "q14": {
            "question": "What is the name of the currency used in Japan?",
            "answer": "The Japanese Yen"
        },
        "q15": {
            "question": "Who was the first man to walk on the moon?",
            "answer": "Neil Armstrong"
        },
        "q16": {
            "question": "Who painted the famous artwork 'The Starry Night'?",
            "answer": "Vincent van Gogh"
        },
        "q17": {
            "question": "What is the name of the famous detective created by Sir Arthur Conan Doyle?",
            "answer": "Sherlock Holmes"
        },
        "q18": {
            "question": "Who composed the famous musical 'The Phantom of the Opera'?",
            "answer": "Andrew Lloyd Webber"
        },
        "q19": {
            "question": "Comprised of pictures and symbols, what is the name of the ancient Egyptian writing system?",
            "answer": "Hieroglyphics"
        },
        "q20": {
            "question": "Which 'G' is the name of the largest moon in our solar system?",
            "answer": "Ganymede"
        }
    },
    "Movie Trivia": {
        "q1": {
            "question": "What make of car has been used by James Bond the most times in the Bond franchise?",
            "answer": "Aston Martin DB5"
        },
        "q2": {
            "question": "Famously, which was the first film, a biblical epic with Richard Burton and Victor Mature, to use Cinemascope?",
            "answer": "The Robe"
        },
        "q3": {
            "question": "What iconic award was designed by Cedric Gibbons and sculpted by George Stanley?",
            "answer": "Oscar"
        },
        "q4": {
            "question": "What is significant about the film 'Oliver Twist' of 1912?",
            "answer": "The first British feature film"
        },
        "q5": {
            "question": "Which film actress was the first African American to represent the USA at a Miss World event?",
            "answer": "Halle Berry"
        },
        "q6": {
            "question": "Who was the first British actor to win an Oscar for his role in 'Private Life of Henry VIII' in 1934?",
            "answer": "Charles Laughton"
        },
        "q7": {
            "question": "Which actor's films included 'Hellcats of the Navy', 'The Killers' and 'Bedtime for Bonzo'?",
            "answer": "Ronald Reagan"
        },
        "q8": {
            "question": "Which film studios were formed by Mary Pickford, Charlie Chaplin, DW Griffith and Douglas Fairbanks in 1919?",
            "answer": "United Artists"
        },
        "q9": {
            "question": "Futureworld was which distinctive actor's final film?",
            "answer": "Yule Brynner"
        },
        "q10": {
            "question": "Who won the Best Actor Oscar for the film 'On the Waterfront'?",
            "answer": "Marlon Brando"
        },
        "q11": {
            "question": "Which 1997 film directed by John Woo stars John Travolta opposite Nicholas Cage?",
            "answer": "Face Off"
        },
        "q12": {
            "question": "What is the of the character played by Brad Pitt in the 1999 film Fight Club?",
            "answer": "Tyler (Duerden)"
        },
        "q13": {
            "question": "Which 1996 Colin Firth film based on a Nick Hornby novel tells the story of Arsenal's title win?",
            "answer": "Fever Pitch"
        },
        "q14": {
            "question": "Tom Cruise plays Lt JG Kaffee and Jack Nicholson is Colonel Jessep in which 1992 film directed by Rob Reiner?",
            "answer": "A Few Good Men"
        },
        "q15": {
            "question": "Which 1996 Robert De Niro films sees a baseball fan kidnap a star player?",
            "answer": "The Fan"
        },
        "q16": {
            "question": "Cher teamed up with directed Paul Mazursky in which 1996 film about a hitman?",
            "answer": "Faithful"
        },
        "q17": {
            "question": "What is the name of Gary Oldman's character in the 1997 film The Fifth Element?",
            "answer": "Zorg"
        },
        "q18": {
            "question": "Who wrote the novel on which the 1993 film 'The Firm' starring Tom Cruise was based?",
            "answer": "John Grisham"
        },
        "q19": {
            "question": "How many Oscars did Forrest Gump win? a) Four b) Five c) Six",
            "answer": "c) Six"
        },
        "q20": {
            "question": "Who plays Fred Flinstone in the 1994 film The Flintstones?",
            "answer": "John Goodman"
        }
    },
    "Geography": {
        "q1": {
            "question": "Which English city on the south coast which features a royal pavillion was named Britain's 'happiest place to live' in 2015?",
            "answer": "Brighton"
        },
        "q2": {
            "question": "Which 'D' is an northern England town on the banks of the River Skerne?",
            "answer": "Darlington"
        },
        "q3": {
            "question": "The River Derwent enters the Irish Sea at which coastal town of Cumbria?  a) Workington b) Hartlepool c) Kendall",
            "answer": "a) Workington"
        },
        "q4": {
            "question": "True or false; there is a village called 'Pity Me' just outside Durham?",
            "answer": "True"
        },
        "q5": {
            "question": "Which town or city is the largest settlement in Scotland beginning with the letter 'D'?",
            "answer": "Dundee"
        },
        "q6": {
            "question": "True or false; Rutland Water is a naturally occuring lake",
            "answer": "False; it was constructed in 1976"
        },
        "q7": {
            "question": "In which English county might you find the towns Darwen and Nelson?",
            "answer": "Lancashire"
        },
        "q8": {
            "question": "Which is taller; the Eiffel Tower or Blackpool Tower?",
            "answer": "Eiffel Tower (324m vs 158m)"
        },
        "q9": {
            "question": "Nevada is famous for its gambling but what is its capital city?",
            "answer": "Carson City"
        },
        "q10": {
            "question": "The region Navarra in the north of Spain has which city, famous for the 'Running of Bulls', as it's capital?",
            "answer": "Pamplona"
        },
        "q11": {
            "question": "What is the name of the highest mountain in the world?",
            "answer": "Mount Everest"
        },
        "q12": {
            "question": "What is the capital city of France?",
            "answer": "Paris"
        },
        "q13": {
            "question": "What is the name of the strait that separates Asia from North America?",
            "answer": "Bering Strait"
        },
        "q14": {
            "question": "What is the name of the mountain range that runs through the western United States?",
            "answer": "The Rocky Mountains"
        },
        "q15": {
            "question": "What is the smallest country in South America by land area?",
            "answer": "Surinam"
        },
        "q16": {
            "question": "Which great American river runs through the Grand Canyon?",
            "answer": "Colorado River"
        },
        "q17": {
            "question": "What is the capital city of Myanmar?",
            "answer": "Naypyidaw"
        },
        "q18": {
            "question": "Which African country is known as the 'Land of a Thousand Hills'?",
            "answer": "Rwanda"
        },
        "q19": {
            "question": "The city of Vancouver is located in which Canadian province?",
            "answer": "British Columbia"
        },
        "q20": {
            "question": "What is the highest mountain in North America?",
            "answer": "Denali aka Mt. McKinley"
        }
    },
    "Sports": {
        "q1": {
            "question": "In Golf, which large seabird gives its name to the score of three-under-par on an indivudual hole?",
            "answer": "Albatross"
        },
        "q2": {
            "question": "Known as 'The Jester from Leicester', which player defeated Shaun Murphy in the final of the World Snooker Championship in 2021?",
            "answer": "Mark Selby"
        },
        "q3": {
            "question": "Which European golfer won the US Open in 2021?",
            "answer": "Jon Rahm"
        },
        "q4": {
            "question": "Which side, newly promoted to the Football League in 2020, play their home games at Wetherby Road?",
            "answer": "Harrogate Town"
        },
        "q5": {
            "question": "Cyclist Mark Cavendish was born on which British Crown Dependency?",
            "answer": "Isle of Man"
        },
        "q6": {
            "question": "Which English sporting venue has the post code HA9 0WS? a) The Olympic Stadium b) Wembley c) Old Trafford",
            "answer": "b) Wembley"
        },
        "q7": {
            "question": "In 2021, Welshman Alun Wyn Jones famously returned to action just 18 days after dislocating his shoulder? Which sport is he best associated with?",
            "answer": "Rugby Union"
        },
        "q8": {
            "question": "Which English football club are known as The Railwaymen?",
            "answer": "Crewe Alexandra"
        },
        "q9": {
            "question": "The Duckworth-Lewis method of calculating the score required to win in a rain affected game of cricket was renamed as what in 2014?",
            "answer": "Duckworth-Lewis-Stern method"
        },
        "q10": {
            "question": "As of 2018 who holds the record for the largest margin of victory for any major at 15 strokes?",
            "answer": "Tiger Woods"
        },
        "q11": {
            "question": "The Jets is the Twenty20 name of which county cricket club, whose limited-overs name was the Dynamos?",
            "answer": "Durham"
        },
        "q12": {
            "question": "Which football team were known as the 'Biscuitmen' up until the 1980's?",
            "answer": "Reading"
        },
        "q13": {
            "question": "The Wall' was a nickname given to which cricketer?",
            "answer": "Rahul Dravid"
        },
        "q14": {
            "question": "Who won his first major championship when beating Justin Rose in a sudden death play-off in Augusta in 2017?",
            "answer": "Sergio Garcia"
        },
        "q15": {
            "question": "What is the highest points total (as of 2018-19) in a season for a team in the English Premier League?",
            "answer": "100"
        },
        "q16": {
            "question": "In the years 2014 to 2019 the London Marathon has been won in 4 of the five races by which African runner?",
            "answer": "Eliud Kipchoge"
        },
        "q17": {
            "question": "Which American city is home to the following sports teams: Rockets, Astros, Texans and Dynamo",
            "answer": "Houston"
        },
        "q18": {
            "question": "Which player scored a free kick against Stoke City to finally surpass Bobby Charlton as Manchester United's all-time leading goalscorer?",
            "answer": "Wayne Rooney"
        },
        "q19": {
            "question": "Bob and Mike Bryan were well known brothers in which sport?",
            "answer": "Tennis"
        },
        "q20": {
            "question": "Which British athlete won gold in both the 5,000 and 10,000 Summer Olympics in 2016?",
            "answer": "Mo Farah"
        }
    },
    "Animals": {
        "q1": {
            "question": "Australian Yorkshire, Kunekune, and Hampshire are breeds of which animal?",
            "answer": "Pig"
        },
        "q2": {
            "question": "True or false, the Hippopotamus has webbed feet?",
            "answer": "True"
        },
        "q3": {
            "question": "In what obvious way does the Indian Rhinoceros differ from the Black Rhinoceros?",
            "answer": "The Indian Rhino only has one horn"
        },
        "q4": {
            "question": "Originating in Norway what kind of animal is a Dunker?",
            "answer": "Dog"
        },
        "q5": {
            "question": "Which are the only birds known to be capable of flying backwards?",
            "answer": "Hummingbird"
        },
        "q6": {
            "question": "Which is the smallest bird in the world? a) Bee Hummingbird b) Willow Tit c) Lesser Goldfinch",
            "answer": "a) Bee Hummingbird"
        },
        "q7": {
            "question": "What special feature does a Salamander have which gives it an advantage when attacked by predators?",
            "answer": "It can drop body parts which it is then able to regrow."
        },
        "q8": {
            "question": "What type of animal is an Ibis?",
            "answer": "Bird"
        },
        "q9": {
            "question": "The Gharial is a slow moving reptile of the crocodile family and is native to which part of the world? a) South America b) Australasia c) Indian subcontinent",
            "answer": "c) Indian subcontinent"
        },
        "q10": {
            "question": "What is the largest predator found on the land in Australia?",
            "answer": "Dingo"
        },
        "q11": {
            "question": "In which part of the world would you find Gophers living in the wild?",
            "answer": "North America"
        },
        "q12": {
            "question": "The Discus is found in the Amazon basin of South America. Is it a) a bird b) a rodent c) a fish",
            "answer": "c) a fish"
        },
        "q13": {
            "question": "The horns of a goat are made out of what substance?",
            "answer": "Keratin"
        },
        "q14": {
            "question": "The Cottontop tamarin is a small species of what type of animal?",
            "answer": "Monkey"
        },
        "q15": {
            "question": "The Dodo which became extinct in the 17th century was native to which island?",
            "answer": "Mauritius"
        },
        "q16": {
            "question": "The Entlebucher mountain dog is native to which mountain region? a) Swiss Alps b) Pyrennees c) Dolomites",
            "answer": "a) Swiss Alps"
        },
        "q17": {
            "question": "Welsh, and Tamworth are breeds of which animal?",
            "answer": "Pig"
        },
        "q18": {
            "question": "Although there are about 60 types of Eagle, only 2 are found in the USA, one is the Bald Eagle but what is the other?",
            "answer": "Golden Eagle"
        },
        "q19": {
            "question": "What is the top speed of a Bottle Nosed Dolphin? a) 21mph b) 26mph c) 31mph",
            "answer": "a) 21mph"
        },
        "q20": {
            "question": "Which animal, found in the waters of South America, has the scientific name of Electrophorus Electricus",
            "answer": "Electric Eel"
        }
    },
    "Politics": {
        "q1": {
            "question": "Former Downing St Press secretary who now champions mental health issues.",
            "answer": "Alastair Campbell"
        },
        "q2": {
            "question": "In the House of Commons, who as of 2016, is the current 'Father of the House'?",
            "answer": "Gerald Kaufman"
        },
        "q3": {
            "question": "Which stately home, by convention, is placed at the disposal of the Chancellor of the Exchequer?",
            "answer": "Dorneywood"
        },
        "q4": {
            "question": "Which US President gave the Gettysburg Address in 1863?",
            "answer": "Abraham Lincoln"
        },
        "q5": {
            "question": "Who was the first US President to visit China? a) Kennedy b) Johnson c) Nixon",
            "answer": "c) Nixon"
        },
        "q6": {
            "question": "Which US President was born in Hawaii in 1961?",
            "answer": "Barack Obama"
        },
        "q7": {
            "question": "Who served as US President between Gerald Ford and Ronald Reagan?",
            "answer": "Jimmy Carter"
        },
        "q8": {
            "question": "Which US President famously got stuck in a bathtub? a) Taft b) Coolidge c) Roosevelt",
            "answer": "a) Taft"
        },
        "q9": {
            "question": "Born in Giffnock, Scotland in 1951, who served at UK Prime Minister between 2007 and 2010?",
            "answer": "Gordon Brown"
        },
        "q10": {
            "question": "Britain's one Prime Minister of Jewish birth, which former UK PM played a major role in the creation of the modern Conservative Party?",
            "answer": "Benjamin Disraeli"
        },
        "q11": {
            "question": "Who is the only Prime Minister to have served under three monarchs (George V, Edward VIII and George VI)?",
            "answer": "Stanley Baldwin"
        },
        "q12": {
            "question": "Known as 'The Grand Old Man', which man served as Prime Minister on four separate occasions between 1868 and 1894?",
            "answer": "William Gladstone"
        },
        "q13": {
            "question": "Who was British Prime Minister during the 'Winter of Discontent' in 1978?",
            "answer": "James Callaghan"
        },
        "q14": {
            "question": "Which former British Prime Minister graduated from Oxford University in 1947 with Second-Class Honours in Chemistry specialising in X-ray crystallogrpahy?",
            "answer": "Margaret Thatcher"
        },
        "q15": {
            "question": "Who became British Prime Minister by default following the withdrawal of Andrea Leadsom from the Conservative Party leadership contest?",
            "answer": "Theresa May"
        },
        "q16": {
            "question": "Which British Prime Minister, born in Broadstairs, Kent in 1916 served as PM between 1970 and 1974?",
            "answer": "Edward Heath"
        },
        "q17": {
            "question": "One important article of the Lisbon treaty must be invoked before Britain can leave the European Union. What is the article's number? a) 15 b) 40 c) 50",
            "answer": "c) 50"
        },
        "q18": {
            "question": "What is the name of the serving Govenor of the Bank of England, who's Friday morning speech is thought to have calmed some of the market chaos?",
            "answer": "Mark Carney"
        },
        "q19": {
            "question": "In which year did Britain originally join the EEC, now known as the European Union? a) 1963 b) 1973 c) 1983",
            "answer": "b) 1973"
        },
        "q20": {
            "question": "Which country followed Slovenia to become the second former Yugoslavian country to join the EU, when it joined in July 2013?",
            "answer": "Croatia"
        }
    },
    "Quick Fire Questions": {
        "q1": {
            "question": "'Anyone Can Fall in Love' is the title of the theme tune of which British soap?",
            "answer": "Eastenders"
        },
        "q2": {
            "question": "What is the first name of the father of English model and photographer Brooklyn Beckham?",
            "answer": "David"
        },
        "q3": {
            "question": "The Ballad of John and Yoko' was the final UK number one single for which band?",
            "answer": "The Beatles"
        },
        "q4": {
            "question": "Which is the only day of the week with nine letters in its name?",
            "answer": "Wednesday"
        },
        "q5": {
            "question": "By area, which is the largest county in England?",
            "answer": "Yorkshire"
        },
        "q6": {
            "question": "Auricular muscles are found in which part of the human body?",
            "answer": "The ear"
        },
        "q7": {
            "question": "Frank Skinner teamed up with which English comedian to write the lyrics to the song 'Three Lions'?",
            "answer": "David Baddiel"
        },
        "q8": {
            "question": "By population, which is the second largest city in Russia?",
            "answer": "Saint Petersburg"
        },
        "q9": {
            "question": "Which car maker produced the Focus, Mondeo and Fiesta models?",
            "answer": "Ford"
        },
        "q10": {
            "question": "Eric Theodore Cartman appears in which animated TV series?",
            "answer": "South Park"
        },
        "q11": {
            "question": "Tripoli is the capital of which North African country?",
            "answer": "Libya"
        },
        "q12": {
            "question": "Which footballer commentator spoke the legendary lines 'Some people are on the pitch, they think it's all over; it is now.'?",
            "answer": "Kenneth Wolstenholme"
        },
        "q13": {
            "question": "Which American comic actor played the title role in the 1996 film Happy Gilmore?",
            "answer": "Adam Sandler"
        },
        "q14": {
            "question": "To make Rocky Road ice cream, ice cream is mixed with chopped nuts, chocolate chips and which other sweet food stuff?",
            "answer": "Marshmallows"
        },
        "q15": {
            "question": "Which word immediately precedes 'Queen' in the opening line of the British National Anthem?",
            "answer": "Gracious"
        },
        "q16": {
            "question": "Which poet wrote 'I Wandered Lonely as a Cloud'?",
            "answer": "William Wordsworth"
        },
        "q17": {
            "question": "The English singer and television presenter Cilla Black was born in which city?",
            "answer": "Liverpool"
        },
        "q18": {
            "question": "Alan Titchmarsh, Charlie Dimmock and Tommy Walsh presented which long-running BBC garden makeover series?",
            "answer": "Ground Force"
        },
        "q19": {
            "question": "Who plays London gangster Jack Carter in the 1971 film Get Carter?",
            "answer": "Michael Caine"
        },
        "q20": {
            "question": "Long time Question of Sport presenter Sue Barker represented Great Britain at which sport?",
            "answer": "Tennis"
        }
    }
}